SUMESH NASKAR

Front-end Developer

Email sumeshnaskar27@gmail.com

<u>Portfolio</u>

Phone +91 8637748846

Meticulous web developer with over 2 years of experience having passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. Experienced working with teams to produce impactful, leading-edge websites that engage customers and deliver business results. Well-versed in design standards and user preferences.

Work History

Apr 2021 – current

Front-end Developer – React

Afourtech Technologies

- Collaborated with clients during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages, dashboards and online applications in React for integration and cross-browser compatibility.
- Engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.
- Reviewed code to validate structures, asses functionality and compatibility.

Sep 2019 – Mar 2021

SDET

Afourtech Technologies

- Developed and executed automated test scripts to handle different features of a product across multiple releases.
- Operated under Agile and Scrum frameworks to complete releases and well-organized sprints.
- Reduced overall testing hours with REST API automation using Python and Golang as languages.
- Designed and developed custom plugin for reflecting real-time execution status.
- Debugged code and located root causes of problems by reviewing configuration files and logs.
- Monitored resolution of bugs, tested fixes and helped tackle ongoing problems by providing QA perspective.

Skills

React, CSS, JavaScript, HTML, Golang, Python, Ansible, Jenkins, Bitbucket, Confluence, JIRA

Education

Feb 2019 – Aug 2021

Post Graduation Diploma in Advanced Computing

ACTS CDAC - Pune